Lawrence Yee

law.yee2133@gmail.com | 347-350-0353 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Brooklyn, NY

Summary

Software engineer with a background in architecture, I have a foundation in mathematics, physics, and visualization approach software development from a rigorous and analytical perspective. With a keen eye for design and an emphasis on user experience, I strive to create elegant and intuitive software solutions that meet the needs of clients and users alike.

Work Experience

Timely Completion

February 2021 - November 2021

Fabricator

- Conducted construction phases with design teams by establishing checkpoints with detailed criteria to be completed
- Developed accurate and precise construction documents, resulting in completion of each phase ahead schedule by estimate of 10% of time allocated to construction

DJ Associates

September 2019 – November 2020

Architecture Designer

- Increased lease renewals for clients via accurate and precise Marketing plans
- Utilized 3D and 2D software to produce precise documents and presentations for both clients and construction
- Actively surveyed job sites in order collect data which ensures accountability for all documents produced

Projects

Endless Bubble Frenzy | GitHub | Deployment

Javascript, HTML, CSS

- Designed and implemented a responsive user interface for a vanilla JavaScript game using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Leveraged display grid to mimic matrix graph
- Optimized game performance and minimized resource usage by implementing efficient algorithms

Architype | GitHub | Deployment

February 2023

Javascript, Three.Js, Rhino3d, WebGL

- Implemented lighting, shading, and texturing to create a realistic and immersive 3D environment.
- Compartmentalized meshes into groups for easy modifications, increases browser loading speed
- Successfully implemented input options for users to dynamically explore the model

Marbler | GitHub | Deployment

January 2023

Javascript, HTML, CSS

- Web-browser game influenced by classic Tron game mixed with pool
- Developed game mechanics and logic, including collision detection, scoring, and game state management.
- Created animations and effects using CSS3 and JavaScript, enhancing the game's visual appeal and user engagement.
- Leveraged jQuery methodologies to grant users full control of their player

Virtual Fit (Hackathon) | GitHub | Deployment

October 2022

React.JS

- Collaboration project with fellow engineers and UX to resolve excess clothing returns for garment industry
- Features: Users may alter their own avatar and adjust for size and gender as well as selection of jeans to select for size comparison.
- Functionality: utilizing react states to implement body proportions for current user, implemented js based css in order to dynamically alter display.
- Role: Engineer the Front end aspect of the project. (Virtual fitting room components + logic behind functionality)

Education

General Assembly Apprenticeship

May 2022

Certification of Completion

2017-2020

New York City college of Technology Bachelors, Architectural Technology

Technical Competencies

- Languages: JavaScript, Python, Java, Ruby
- Frontend Tools: ReactJS, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Creative, Three.JS, 3D Modeling
- Backend Tools: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Django, PostgreSQL, Mongoose, Flask
- Tools: Github, Git, Heroku, Netlify, Postman, Chrome DevTool, Agile
- Certifications: Certification of Completion in Software Development (General Assembly), Forage Software Engineering Virtual Experience (JP Morgan Chase & Co.)